LUKE EDWARDS

JUNIOR FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

SUMMARY

Junior web developer with a diploma in full-stack web development from the Code Institute. I am proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python and many other libraries and frameworks. I have eight years of experience working in the music industry as a guitarist, author and sole trader, and one-year experience working at a leading graphic design and web-development agency in Pembrokeshire. I pride myself on being a valuable team-player with strong communication skills and effective problem-solving abilities. I am enthusiastic about joining the tech industry where I can further grow my skillset, contribute to a team and hone my abilities as a developer.



Address: Carmarthen, Carmarthenshire SA311FF

Phone: 07581238286

Email: luketedmusic@gmail.com

Links:

GitHubLinkedIn

EDUCATION

Level 5 Diploma in Full Stack Development, Full Stack Web Development, 2022

Code Institute - Dublin

Intensive one-year long web development course accredited by the University of West Scotland.

BA Hons, Popular Music, 2018 Leeds Conservatoire - Leeds

I trained at the prestigious Leeds conservatoire. Modules I undertook include film music, performance, composition, arranging, music business and music education.

SKILLS

- Languages: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python, PHP
- Frameworks: Django, Flask, Bootstrap, Materialize, WordPress
- Databases: MySQL, SQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Amazon S3 & AWS
- Libraries: React, Tailwind, jQuery
- Platforms & Technologies: Heroku, GitHub, Git
- Other software: Photoshop/Affinity photo, InDesign/ Affinity Publisher, Adobe illustrator/ Affinity Designer, Logic Pro X, Guitar Pro, Final Cut, Figma, Microsoft Word/PowerPoint/Excel.

PORTFOLIO PROJECTS

- <u>Hiraeth Guitars</u> A static website designed for a fictional guitar luthier. **Technologies Used** HTML, CSS, Bootstrap.
- <u>Pokergraphic Memory</u> An interactive card memorization game which tasks the player to memorize the order of a deck of playing cards using ancient memory techniques. The project features teaching material to make this possible for the user, and measures past performance to track progress. <u>Technologies Used</u> - HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, JavaScript, jQuery.
- <u>Harmonize</u> A social network platform designed to help musicians find suitable collaborators. The project features a fully realized friends' system, profile pages, messaging between users, groups and projects, file uploading and sharing etc. <u>Technologies Used</u> - HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flask, MongoDB, Amazon S3. <u>GitHub</u>
- <u>Score Emporium</u> A full-stack e-commerce platform similar to eBay, which allows musicians to both sell and buy interactive musical scores. Features include an in-browser interactive score player for users to listen to scores, a sales dashboard which presents vendors with useful data, automatic watermarking for vendor products, stripe

- card payments, a review system. **Technologies Used -** HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Django, PostgreSQL, Amazon S3.
- My personal business website My personal business website built in 2018 using WordPress. It acts as both a webpage for my services and also as an e-commerce platform to sell musical scores. Technologies Used - WordPress, various plugins like WooCommerce, jetpack etc.

EXPERIENCE

Web Developer, 10/2021 - Current

Design Marque

- 1-year professional experience working with leading Pembrokeshire based web development/graphic design company, <u>Design Marque</u>.
- Experience working with both WordPress and HTML, CSS and JavaScript to build client websites and contact forms.
- Examples of my responsibilities include building contact forms for websites, fixing WordPress issues and bugs, improving existing sites' SEO or performance, running Facebook and Google advertising campaigns, creating marketing content for adverts etc.

Contributing Author to Acoustic Guitar Magazine, 12/2021 - Current Self employed

Link to digital version of article on AGM website

- I wrote an extensive article exploring traditional Welsh folk music and Celtic guitar techniques in the context of solo acoustic guitar.
- I filmed, edited and produced audio for a 25-minute video tutorial of the lesson.
- Composed, transcribed and edited accompanying sheet music scores and exercises.

Author of 'Songs of Wales for Fingerstyle Guitar', 12/2021 - Current Self-employed, published by Mel Bay Publications

Link to book on Mel Bay's Website

- I wrote and produced a full-length book for major American publisher 'Mel Bay'. The book consisted of 17 pieces of traditional Welsh folk repertoire which I arranged for solo acoustic guitar.
- The publication was accompanied by full playthroughs of all pieces in the book, and also historical information surrounding each tune.
- All pieces in the book were arranged, scored, recorded, and edited by me.
- I wrote, edited, and formatted all written content for the book.

Self Employed Guitar Teacher/Performer. 01/2018 - Current **Self Employed**

- Since 2018 I have operated as a sole trader working as a guitar tutor, performer and recording artist.
- As a sole trader, I have taken on and learned many different roles, including marketing, SEO, running an e-commerce platform to sell my own scores and material, building my own website, recording and editing video, and audio, and many other tasks.
- My tutoring business grew to be the highest rated and ranked on Google for my local city of Cardiff.
- As a performer and recording musician I have worked internationally with many prominent artists. Notably this includes a large project for renowned producer and Youtuber (250,000 + subscribers) Alex Rome, for whom I created and recorded hundreds of samples for an EDM loop pack.